Nian CHEN

Tel: (1)323-630-7114; Email: nianchen@usc.edu

EDUCATION

2022.08-now University of Southern California

Master of Fine Arts (Interactive Media Game Design)

2015.02-2018.12 Monash University

Bachelor of Informatics and Computation Advanced (Honor)

PORTFOLIO

 $\frac{https://drive.google.com/file/d/10yBwWo16SGLP_yUxfX_HewFiYovDs6v0/view?}{usp=drivesdk}$

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

2018 AR Interactive Map

Designed the optimised way to add, remove, reorder and re-symbolise map layers for interactive map in immersive environment

Produced two operation demos, inviting the researchers to simulate modules and record relevant data

2018.02-2018.06 Tutor for Android and iOS Development project

Helped students build demos, answered their questions about how to design and develop a simple App.

Instructed students to follow the tutorial to accomplish each assignment and marked their assignments with detailed comments.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2020.07-2022.06

Beijing Hortor Games Company

Member of Innovation Department, Full-time

- Produced a multiplayers puzzle system plugin for UE4. And finished a two-players room escape game based on that.
- Produced a paper-based murder mystery game. Designed the whole story, mysteries and all the characters.
- Helped the department keep in touch with the latest tools and technologies, read official documents with good English proficiency.

2019.03-2020.03

Beijing Hortor Games Compan Game Developer in Project Team, Full-time

- Responsible for simplifying the traditional TPS/FPS games to enable more users to acknowledge the charm of shooting games
- Accomplished work tasks effectively, including front-end UI, shooting and weapon system, control character animation, etc.

2021.03-2022.06

Rosso Fashion&Arts Education Game Design Consultant, Part-time

- Give lessons to students. Teach them to develop games in Unreal or Unity engine.
- For some specific design that student cannot come true by their own, I assist as a consultant to direct them find a solution.

HONOURS AND AWARDS

2015-2018	Monash International Merit Scholarship
2017	Information Technology Industry-Based Learning Placement Scholarship
2022	"Amrita Karuk avagga", Best Student Game for IndiePlay China 2022

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

3D Games Development

• Platform: Unity & UE4

• Language: C#, C++, Blueprint

Web Game / WeChat MiniGame/ TikTok MiniGame Development

- Platform: Egret Engine & Cocos Creator Engine
- Language: TypeScript

Familiar with narrative game tools like Fungus

Narrative story writing

Game mechanism design

FAVORITE GAMES

Cyberpunk 2077 (80h)

Legend Of Zelda: Breath Of The Wild (155h)

Elden Ring (151h)

To The Moon

The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim (75h)

Personal Statement

Hello, my name is Nian Chen, and I am a game designer pursuing my MFA in Interactive Media and Games at the University of Southern California.

My journey as a game designer started in high school. I was captivated by Sword Art Online, a light novel about virtual reality technology. The idea of AR/VR really resonated with me, and I was inspired to pursue a career in the field. To this day, I still have a passion for AR/VR technologies. I believe that the line between the virtual world and reality is becoming blurred. Someday, the virtual world will be an integral part of our lives.

In the second year of my bachelor degree, I participated in my first VR/AR project: a simulator for medical students to practice suturing skills. The project was developed in Unity and used Leap Motion to support gesture detection. With the help of my supervisor,I have gained a basic understanding and knowledge of academic research.In the third year, I joined another team researching AR sandbox. We used Kinect to collect the terrain data from the sandbox and simulated it in Unity for other projects.I attempted to construct a forest rainfall model using these data, although I failed, I still learned a lot from the experience.

In the research project of my honors degree, I was responsible for the design of the way to add, remove, reorder and re-symbolize layers of interactive maps in immersive environments. With the supervision of my tutor, I developed two sets of operation schemes for the interactive map layer controlled in an immersive environment. These two demos used Unity3D as the engine, MapBox library as the support of map function, leap motion as the hand tracking solution, and HTC Vice Pro to display immersive scenes and interactive interfaces.

After that, I worked in Beijing Hortor Games for three years as a developer and narrative creator. This precious experience greatly heightened my professional skill on game design and development. Knowledge that I'd learned about game engines, VR and gesture recognition helped me develop the demo of "SwordSpeed"--a game based on Chinese traditional tales in which mortals can fly by standing on their swords. Likewise, in "SwordSpeed", the player can stand on a sword to fly and use the "mudra" to control the speed and direction.

Overall, I have a great enthusiasm for AR/VR techniques. Through my experiences in computation, research projects and game design, I am confident that I will be able to contribute to the team, as well as learn a lot about AR/VR technologies.